WILLIAM PLUMB

1922 N 840 W, Provo, UT 84604 | (C) 4352517970 | zrenicaplumb@gmail.com

• http://informationproliferation.com/portfolio2/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Web Developer committed to maintaining cutting edge technical skills and up-to-date industry knowledge. Have extensive experience with HTML & CSS. Working on expanding my skill base with Javascript, jQuery and PHP.

I'm and open person and i try to be straightforward in my communication with others. I am 100% open and receptive to help and criticism and understand that the more you learn, the more questions there are. Any help or tips offered on ways to improve my work/skills are greatly appreciated.

SKILLS

- Product templates
- Coding and modularization
- Excellent diagnostic skills
- Website maintenance
- Fluent in Polish
- Elementary speaking levels in order from most to least fluent: Spanish, Russian, Japanese, archaic language dilettante
- Good interpersonal skills
- Good attention to detail.
- Creating my own human language

- HTML and CSS
- basic PHP skills (want to learn more and get into back end work with databases)
- Bootstrap
- Beginning Javascript
- Beginning jQuery
- Site Design

WEB DEVELOPMENT &

WORK HISTORY

JULY 2017-SEPTEMBER 2017

Hiatus - Lived in Poland for several months, backpacked | Kraków and Wrocław

APRIL 2016-JULY 2017

Web Developer | Utah Valley University | Orem, UT

Worked/working primarily with HTML and CSS. Currently working as an Area Support Web Developer for the UVU College of Humanities and Social Sciences. Handle support tickets for problems that need fixing related to the CHSS department and sometimes other departments as well. Worked with a team to publish the Roots of Knowledge interactive website for the Roots of Knowledge Window. Have redesigned and rebuilt numerous UVU webpages and websites alone as well as with a team.

Coordinated with systems partners to finalize designs and confirm requirements.

- Implemented company policies, technical procedures and standards for preserving the integrity and security of data, reports and access.
- Managed creative projects from concept to completion while managing outside vendors.

FEBRUARY 2015-MAY 2015

Intern/Web Developer Aptivada | Saint George

Had first exposure to web development and web languages. Gained desire to enter this field after seeing all the cool stuff in action at a small company. Worked on small things and spent most of my time learning.

AUGUST 2014-JULY 2015

Captioncall Translator | Captioncall | Saint George, UT

Translated incoming calls intended for deaf people who are unable to hear whom they are talking to. Would say aloud what the deaf person needed to hear on the call and words would be printed onto a special phone screen for them to read.

JULY 2013-MAY 2014

Distributor Support Representative | Nu Skin | Provo, Utah

Handled shipping, order placement, and customer/Distributor support telephone lines for Distributors of Nu Skin products who were from various areas of the globe. 70% of the work entailed solving personal and varied issues and problems for aforementioned Distributors.

NOVEMBER 2012-APRIL 2013

Operations Crew | Utah Valley Convention Center | Provo, UT

Member of operations crew, in charge of set-up and care of functions, meetings and conventions of all sizes.

APRIL 2012-AUGUST 2012

Diamond Drill Bit Polisher | US Synthetic | Orem, UT

Part of the polishing department at US synthetic. Sometimes assembled parts to be made into diamond hard pieces which were sold to oil companies to drill for oil in various regions of the world.

NOVEMBER 2009-NOVEMBER 2011

Missionary LDS Church | Poland

JANUARY 2009-OCTOBER 2009

Set-up Crew, Banquet Server | Marriott Hotel | Saint George, UT

Instrumental in all set-up processes involving furniture and decoration of rental rooms throughout the hotel. Instrumental in food service at company functions and banquets.

NOVEMBER 2007-MAY 2008

Pizza maker, Baker, Cutter | Hungry Howie's Pizza | Saint George, UT Made Pizza.

EDUCATION

.....

CURRENT

Web Design and Development - Application Development:

Utah Valley University, Orem, UT

2009

High School Diploma:

Desert Hills High School Saint George

REFERENCES

Nathan Gerber - Supervisor, Utah Valley University Web Dev. Dept.

Nathan.Gerber@uvu.edu

801-863-7973

Bryan Green - Owner, Aptivada

435-229-3742